He's not a serial killer. He's much worse.
Dust Devil is a horror, mystery, thriller film directed by Richard Stanley.
A woman on the run from her abusive husband encounters a mysterious hitch-hiker.
Dust Devil, played by Robert John Burke.
Wendy Robertson, played by Chelsea Field.
Dr. Leidzinger, played by Marianne Sägebrecht.
Capt. Cornelius Beyman, played by William Hootkins.
Ben Mukurob, played by Zakes Mokae.
Joe Niemand, played by John Matshikiza.
Dust Devil is a 1992 British horror film written
and directed by Richard Stanley.
The film stars Robert Burke as Hitch, a mysterious man who wanders the deserts in Namibia and is wanted by the
police in connection with the death of a woman whose blood was used in a supernatural ceremony.
It is believed by a local sangoma that Hitch is a "Dust Devil", a
supernatural creature that can change its form.
Hitch encounters Wendy, played by Chelsea Field, who drives with him
along a highway as she is pursued by her estranged husband.
As police begin investigating the murders, they seem to trace back to
Hitch and Wendy discovers the man has supernatural powers.
Dust Devil was shot in Namibia after March 1990, when Stanley presented his script to producer
JoAnne Sellar, whom he had previously worked with on his first film Hardware (1990).
Sellar was able to secure 2.8 million pounds for Dust Devil.
The script was then sent to the Ministry of Information
and Broadcasting in Namibia for approval.
Sellar was also able to use South African personnel and equipment for the production, making the
film's crew a combination of British, American, South African and Namibian people.
After finishing filming, Dust Devil experienced a difficult post-production, with several different cuts being released in the United
Kingdom, the United States and select areas in Europe, where the film was released in a much shorter version titled Demonica.
In 1993, the film was released in United Kingdom following the demise of
Palace Pictures under an end credit of Dust Devil: The Final Cut.
It was released in the United States by Miramax with a
shorter running time than the British version.
The film explores themes of adultery, fire, dreams, wind, nightmare.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.